3648 Sunset Ridge Rd. Altadena, CA 91001 jeffolive@gmail.com LinkedIn.com/in/jeffolive (626) 616-4196

Information Technology Engineer

Technology leader, people manager, and engineer experienced in the introduction of new IT, security, and workforce capabilities as well as overseeing on-going systems operations. Skilled in developing people, envisioning roadmaps, driving digital workplace initiatives, and building business and vendor partnerships.

Areas of expertise include:

- IT Leadership
- Coaching and Development
- Strategic Planning

- Office 365 Admin and Migration
- Operational Management
- Financial Management
- Technology Strategy
- Enterprise Architecture
- Infrastructure Design

Professional Experience

Aegon Transamerica

Manager, Workforce Management – Office 365 Services

2016 - Present

Service owner for global, hybrid Office 365 collaboration services. Lead an agile team in strategic programs, infrastructure initiatives, and production operations. Servant leader, technical architect, operations manager, vendor and contract manager, budget owner, and business partner.

Key Results:

- Deployed Office 365 services for global workforce
- Migrated 30,000 mailboxes to Exchange Online in 6 months utilizing custom automation
- Transitioned 10,000 mobile users from Good to Intune
- Developed governance and deployed Teams, OneDrive, SharePoint, Yammer, Flow, PowerApps
- Received EU regulatory approval for cloud services (data privacy, data processing, data sovereignty)
- Implemented Security: Azure AD, Conditional Access, eDiscovery, Privileged Identity, Info Protection, B2B Guest
- Co-developed end-user adoption strategy: Started Change Champions, Customer Immersion, Early Adopters
- Member of company Project Review Committee and Initiative Review Board

Manager, Workforce and Client Technology Engineering

2011 - 2016

Developed workforce service roadmaps and drove initiatives to implement modern workplace and collaborative services. Partnered with business units to ensure solutions aligned with objectives by modeling segmentation models, testing hypotheses with interviews, and facilitating customer focus groups to understand current and emerging requirements. Proposed and introduced new technologies by delivering on roadmaps, developing business cases, and agile delivery MVP proof-of-concepts. Implemented new solutions with Operations and supported their needs to turn-up services into business as usual.

Key Results:

- Managed service and people, including budget, service catalog and cost accounting/recovery, numerous risk assessments, audits, and compliance engagements.
- Restructured Workforce Management organization and led Workforce Engineering with other Heads (of Operations and Service Management)
- **Led initiatives to boost workforce productivity** by introducing desktop and application virtualization for increased deployment agility and support of a wider variety of laptops and mobile devices.

Jeff Olive – Resume, Page 2 of 3

- Sponsored numerous initiatives supporting workforce productivity, including the design and implementation of
 a 5-year Unified Communications strategy, BYOD mobile device services, BYOC laptop option, regulatory
 compliance archiving capability, and video on-demand hosting.
- Led the design and implementation of the first Global Intranet based on SharePoint including the introduction of social communities, including people profiles, microblogs, forums, rating/tagging, and search.
- Led contract negotiations on numerous agreements, including up to \$30MM Microsoft Enterprise Agreement.

Manager of Internet, Messaging, Directory Services, and Enterprise Application Integration 1996 - 2011

Led 35-member top-tier devops engineering and operations team supporting Internet-facing and intranet applications. Responsible for production high availability and change management. Services focused on enterprise solutions for internal business units, including ISP services like application hosting and Internet security, email, hosted instant messaging utility, and enterprise directory services.

Key Results:

- Integrated and consolidated dozens of disparate company email systems initially by implementing a complex X.500 translational gateway platform, then by migrating to a robust Exchange 2010 utility service.
- **Built a robust, centralized Internet hosting utility** used by all Aegon U.S. business units, including direct marketing applications, 401K participant/sponsor sites, and insurance B2B and B2C applications. Key performance indicators included: high availability and security management performance, effective use of technology, superior customer service, and cost efficiency that was regularly benchmarked.
- Increased network security and improved Windows administration efficiency by implementing the enterprise Active Directory and consolidating dozens of disparate NT domains.
- Enhanced web security and improved Aegon's customer experience by implementing a centralized Identity Management infrastructure utilizing Oracle's web single sign-on for access management and authorization.
- Met regulatory compliance and enabled numerous competitive advantages through technology by implementing secure email, SEC/NASD-compliant email archiving, anti-spam/malware controls, and support for mobile messaging.
- Improved data quality throughout the enterprise by establishing a data synchronization/replication utility for numerous administrative databases and directories across the company.

Capitol – EMI Records Group, North America

Director of Network Design and Operations, Telecommunications Manager

1993 - 1996

Promoted from Manager based on demonstrated leadership, business acumen, and the ability to deliver results. Managed a distributed team responsible for voice and data projects, adds/moves/changes, network incident management, and technical support for the North American systems infrastructure. Remote management required significant coaching. Personally performed the highest level of technical architecture and detailed design, project/resource/vendor management, and operational support in a multi-protocol, multi-system, voice and data environment. Required extensive experience and a detailed understanding of system integration and operations for voice, LAN, WAN, and video systems. Developed and managed annual IT communications budget (\$4M) and oversaw contract management and administration.

Key Results:

- **Engineered and transformed the North American network** by transitioning systems to TCP/IP and eliminating the expensive and inflexible, legacy SNA network supporting dozens of sites.
- **Improved operational effectiveness and production costs** by planning and implementing the relocation of the primary data/network center from Los Angeles to New York.
- Increased standardization (process, system, customer satisfaction) by consolidating management of telephone voicemail, and video conferencing systems through increased remote management of local staff and systems.

Home Savings of America

Senior Engineer, Corporate Telecommunications

1991 - 1993

Performed primary technical design, system integration consulting, and project implementation leadership for LAN and WAN networks. Responsible for all network changes including all router configurations. Managed 3rd level problem resolution for network equipment. Provided theoretical and hands-on practical training to 1st and 2nd level support teams.

Key Results:

- **Enabled enhanced business functionality** by leading the planning and implementation of router-connected LANs in Home Savings branch offices.
- Significantly increased network availability at the Home Savings campus by designing and implementing an
 upgraded LAN distribution system that enabled proactive monitoring for errors. Managed the \$400K project budget.
 Separately, overhauled the network from a hodgepodge of bridging devices to a managed Cisco routed network
 covering 10 buildings, dozens of networks, and numerous remote connections. Managed the \$300K project budget.

First Interstate Bank

Project Leader, Network Services Group

1990 - 1991

Provided technical consulting and technical account management for data center services to three major divisions of the bank. Provided data and telecommunication solutions to support the client's business requirements. Performed project matrix management of technical resources for projects from developing business requirements through implementation.

Western Digital

Senior Network Engineer

1988 - 1990

Responsible for supporting numerous voice and data production systems as well as performing technical design and project management in support of new business requirements.

Key Results:

- Project managed the successful build-out and relocation of company offices by developing a highly specialized voice and data infrastructure and by facilitating the design and build out of the data center facilities.
 Administered contracts and supervised work for three new buildings, over 3500 stations, including a new 14-story high rise and a semiconductor plant.
- Supported the business's rapid demand for growth by assisting in the plan, installation, and network integration of 8 new AT&T Definity PBX's.

Education and Certifications

Microsoft MCSE: Mobility 2017
Microsoft MCSE: Productivity 2017

Microsoft MCSA: Office 365 Microsoft MCSA: Windows 10

Certified Information Systems Security Professional (CISSP)

Citrix Certified Expert – Virtualization (CCE-V)

California Licensed Professional Electrical Engineer (PE)

MBA, USC Marshall School of Business BS – Electrical Engineering, UC Irvine